Guide to the Phi Delta Kappa, Alpha Gamma Chapter Records 1917-1966
Washington State University Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)
Phi Delta Kappa, Alpha Gamma Chapter Records
1917-1966
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Terrell Library Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 127
Phi Delta Kappa, Alpha Gamma Chapter
13 containers. 6.5 linear feet of shelf space.
Financial and membership records, newsletters, minutes, correspondence, and other records of the chapter, including those of its predecessor, the Alpha Beta club.
Phi Delta Kappa is a national education honorary. The local chapter was first established as the Alpha Beta Club in 1917. The club successfully petitioned Phi Delta Kappa for chapter standing and the Alpha Gamma Chapter was established in 1922.
This collection consists of records of the Alpha Gamma Chapter of Phi Delta Kappa. It contains minutes, correspondence, financial and membership records, convention materials, and newsletters.
The Records of the Alpha Gamma Chapter of Phi Delta Kappa are arranged in seven series: Correspondence, Minutes, Financial Records, Newsletters, Other Records, Membership Account Records, and the Membership Roll. Within each series, except for the alphabetically arranged membership accounts and the numerically arranged membership rolls, the materials have been kept in chronological order. Some overlap exists, however, as the succeeding officers changed record-keeping practices.
This collection is open for research use.
The records of the Alpha Gamma Chapter of the national education honorary Phi Delta Kappa were deposited in the Washington State University Library by the WSU College of Education in April 1976. An earlier portion was deposited in 1974.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Phi Delta Kappa. Alpha Gamma Chapter (Washington State University) --Archives; Washington State University--Students--Societies, etc.; Alpha Beta Club (Pullman, Wash.)
Education -- Washington (State)--Societies, etc.--Records and correspondence
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - [principally 1917-1921, concerning efforts to establish a local chapter], 1917-1950; 125 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1927-1936, 50 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - (45th Year), 1953-1954; 40 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - (45th Year), 1953-1954; 50 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1957-1958, 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters to prospective members., 1958-1959; 80 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1961-1962, 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1962-1963, 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1965-1966, 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2: Minutes
  - inc. "Chapter Activities" handbook, 1921-1923; 3 volumes. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1924-1928, 2 volumes. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1938-1947, 1 volume. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1940-1941, 2 volumes. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1955, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1956-1957, 1 volume. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1958, 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1959-1960, 30 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1959-1964, 45 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1959-1964, 50 items. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1960-1961, 25 items. (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Series 3: Financial Records
  - 1925-1930, 1 volume. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1930-1937, 3 volumes. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1937-1941, 3 volumes. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1939-1949, 2 volumes. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, membership information and papers relating to finances., 1946-1947; 50 items. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - correspondence and other papers relating to finances., 1947-1949; 35 items. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - correspondence, membership information, papers and documents relating to finances., 1949-1950; 100 items. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 1949-1954, 2 volumes. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - (43rd Year) correspondence, membership dues reports, papers and documents relating to finances., 1951-1952; 175 items. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - (44th Year) correspondence, membership dues files, papers and documents relating to finances., 1952-1953; 130 items. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - (45th Year) bills, receipts and financial statements., 1953-1954; 50 items. (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - treasurer's records., 1954-1958; 80 items. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - (48th Year) by-laws and "Chapter Officers' Handbooks"., 1956-1957; 15 items. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - annual financial report., 1964-1965; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Series 4: Newsletters
  - Alpha Gamma News, 1925-1966; 45 items. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Editorial Working Papers, undated; 30 items. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Other newsletters, 1955-1959; 20 items. (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Series 5: Other Records
  - Initiation Materials- initiation information and sample certificate of membership., undated; 4 items. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Forms; working papers, correspondence and convention materials; samples of official PDK documents and handouts, working papers file, undated; 35 items. (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - 24th Biennial Council Convention, 1953; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - 26th Biennial Council Convention, 1957; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - 27th Biennial Council Convention, 1959; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Series 6: Membership Account records
  - A - K (Box 7)
  - L - Z (Box 8)
- Series 7: Membership records- Personal History of Candidates
  - #1-81 (Box 8)
  - #82-300 (Box 9)
  - #301-625 (Box 10)
  - #626-970 (Box 11)
  - #971-1290 (Box 12)
  - #1291-1645 (plus duplicates) (Box 13)